the Russian Federation was formed in 1991
российской Федерации образовалась в 1991
super that is, you have a young state
супер то есть у вас молодое государство
yes
да
m republic yes I understand
м республика да понял
exactly the state yes the country is quite
именно государство да страна достаточно
ancient relatively more precisely in the sense the
древня относительно точнее в смысле
country is relatively ancient that is since
страна относительно древня то есть с
ninety-one how ancient it is
девяносто первого года как она древняя
not exactly this state that is a
не именно это государство то есть
specific power form of government
конкретная власть форма правления
administration specific
администрация конкретная
not a state but as a country quite a
не государство а как страна достаточно
long time ago and what is a country then if not a
давно а что такое страна тогда если не
state
государство
hello hello
здравствуйте
I am from the city of Khmelnitsky where are you
здравствуйте я из города Хмельницкий вы
from
откуда
I am from the city of Donetsk and now where
я из города Донецк а сейчас где
there in Donetsk were you born or came from
там же в Донецке родились или приехали
somewhere well I have been
откуда-то
living yes quite a long time already
ну живу да довольно давно уже там
since what year well
это с какого года
somehow you ask too many questions
ну как-то вы сильно много вопросов
well there before the Maidan after the Maidan
задаёте ну там до Майдана после Майдана
before the Maidan yes super then you basically
до Майдана да супер то вы в принципе
witnessed all these births of the DPR yes well of
застали все эти рождения ДНРА да
course I understand can you tell me that it is
ну конечно понял можете мне вот сказать
very good finally I met a
вот очень хорошо наконец-то я встретил
person who witnessed all
человека который был свидетелем всех
these events
этих событий
all the Russians tell me that the
мне все русские говорят что боевые
hostilities in Donetsk and in the Donetsk region
действия в Донецке и в Донецкой области
were before Strelkov entered
были до того как Стрелков зашёл с
Slavyansk with an armed detachment  April 12
вооружённым отрядом в Славянск 12 апреля
and I ask no one can tell me
и я спрашиваю никто мне не может сказать
after all what happened can you tell me were there
всё ж таки что было можете сказать были
any military actions uh before
какие-то военные действия ээ до того как
Russian militants captured the city of
российские боевики захватили город
Slavin since April 13
Славин с 13 апреля
yes I know now so clearly I ca
да знаю сейчас так прямо чётко вам
n't formulate the chronology for you but
хронологию не с не сформулирую но
starting from 2014 maybe
начиная с четырнадцатого года может быть
from 2015 now there have been active direct
с пятнадцатого вот уже активные прямо
combat no then it's already clear yes I
боевые нет тогда уже понятно да я имею в
mean that the Russians say that it was
виду что россияне говорят что это
Ukraine that started blah-blah-blah
Украина начала там бла-бла-бла
well in Kyiv there was its own Maidan the residents of
ну в в Киеве свой майдан был жители
Donetsk Lugansk did not agree with this
Донецка Луганска с этим не согласны были
therefore they are
поэтому они
against let's say so uh the government that
против скажем так ээ той власти которая
replaced Yanukovych well uh their well here
пришла на смену Януковича вот ээ их ну у
it's called a junta well yes yes well
нас это называется хунта вот да да ну
it's a junta I just can't understand like
это хунта я просто не могу понять типа
what are the Russians trying to answer me no no I'm
что мне россияне пытаюсь ответить нене
interested in military actions
мне меня интересуют военные действия
junta all I'm interested in were
хунта это всё меня интересует были ли
there any punitive
приходили там какие-то карательные
battalions Pravo Sektor came there they
батальоны Право сектора там
shot people in short there was something like that
расстреливали людей короче было что-то
but how could they well
такое так а как они могли
personally I didn't see  so that they
ну ну лично я не видел чтобы
would shoot
расстреливали
but there are videos on the Internet and how would it be And who and who
но ролики есть в интернете да и как бы А
started the military actions
кто а кто на кто начал боевые действия
military actions well as Strelkov said
боевые действия ну как сказал Стрелков
he pulled the trigger he he yes that is everything is
на курок нажал он он да то есть всё
correct that is Russian militants here are
правильно то есть российские боевики тут
correct you see no nili residents of
правильно видите никакие нили жители
Donbass also it is also interesting Strelkov is
Донбасса ещё тоже интересно стрелков же
not a Russian militant still a
ж это ж не российский боевик ещё
Russian militant yes a citizen of the
российский боевик да гражданин
Russian Federation a resident of the city of
Российской Федерации житель города
Moscow yes an employee of the special services question:
Москва да сотрудник спецслужб вопрос:
who was the first head of the DPR you know
кто был первым главой ДНР вы же знаете
your republic
ваша республика
uh yes now I will tell you in the square he constantly
ээ да сейчас скажу на площади постоянно
spoke well don't wait there until until Well you
выступал ну не подождите там до до Ну вы
probably asked about Zakharchenko no no
наверное про Захарченко спрашивали нет
until Zakharchenko was until until Zakharchenko
нет до Захарченко был до до Захарченко
was damn well he too Where is he
был блин ну он тоже Где же он сейчас он
now is he fighting now in
сейчас воюет
my opinion Gubarev no no Gubarev
по-моему губарев во нет нет Губарев не
was not the head of the DPR never well
был главой ДНР никогда
Zakharchenko no until Zakharchenko was
ну Захарченко нет до Захарченко был
Zakharchenko already did uh then in the
захарченко уже сделали э-э потом аж
summer in August before the Minsk
летом в августе перед Минскими
agreements I don't know now I'll google well come on
соглашениями не знаю сейчас загуглю а ну
who was the first head of your
давайте кто же был первой главой вашей
young republic
молодой республики
well Zakharchenko the first  first from what from
ну Захарченко первая первая с какого с
what date from what date a-ta-ta-ta
какой даты с какой даты а та-та-та-та
so the first head of Donetsk was
так первым главой Донецкой нароблен был
Vladimir Zakharchenko he held this
Владимир Захарченко он занимал эту
position from the moment of the official
должность с момента официального
entry on November 4, fourteenth
вступления с 4 ноября четырнадцатого
year November 4 so stop and you had
года 4 ноября так стоп а у вас до 4
someone before November 4 really you had the DPR
ноября кто-то был правда у вас ДНР
formed there apre no no no no
образовалось же ещё там апре нет нет нет
would And now look at Borodai
нет бы А теперь посмотри бородай
Alexander Borodai you had well a
александр Бородай был у вас был
beard - this is in my opinion in this or in
ну борода- это по-моему в этом или или в
Donetsk there is no
Донецке нет
beard on Google you
бородава на Гугле
just constantly
нагле просто постоянно
throw in the same Wait stop stop stop stop stop
накидываете у вас же Подожди стоп стоп
no look again that
стоп стоп стоп нет смотри ещё раз то
is until yes until November you had
есть до да до ноября месяца был у вас
some Borodai a resident of the city of Moscow yes
какой-то бородай житель города Москва да
uh this citizen of the Russian Federation is
э-э этот гражданин Российской Федерации
now a deputy uh of the State Duma how did it
сейчас депутат ээ Государственной Думы
happen that the
был как у вас так получилось что встал
people of Donbass stood up and a resident of the city of Moscow became the head of the republic a
народ Донбасса а главой республики стал
citizen of Russia
житель города Москва гражданин России
uh a resident of the city of Moscow became the Minister of Defense a citizen of Russia
ээ министром обороны стал житель города
Strelkov uh the Ministry of Internal Affairs
Москва гражданин России Стрелков ээ МВД
became a resident of the city of
стал житель города
Moscow how so
Москва как так
look let's make sure  we had a dialogue,
смотрите давайте чтобы у нас был диалог
like you ask a question, I answer you,
как бы вопрос вы задаёте я вам отвечаю
then I ask you a question, if you can
потом вопрос я вам вы если можете
answer, otherwise you just
отвечать а то вы как-то просто
throw it on and on, yes, that is,
накидываете накидываете да то есть
let's answer this and ask a
давайте ответьте на это и зададите
question, otherwise I wanted to ask and you
вопрос а то уже хотел спросить а вы
ran off somewhere, well, I
куда-то убежали ну я вам там на
answered several questions there, tell me,
несколько вопросов ответил скажите у вас
when the Maidan happened in Kyiv, you
когда майдан в Киеве происходил у вас же
also immediately
там тоже сразу там не не президента
chose a president, didn't you have some transitional
выбрали у вас же там какие-то переходные
personalities there, right, yes, yes, absolutely
личности правильно да да да абсолютно
right, yes, absolutely, they were absolutely
верно да да абсолютно они были абсолютно
right, that's no, no, no, look,
правильно это нет нет нет нет смотри это
Teyagnebok was never the head of
Теягнебок никогда не был главой
state, look, but there was Turchynov, no, no,
государства смотри но был Турчинов нет
stop, there was Turchynov, yes,
нет стоп был был Турчинов да исполняющий
acting, then Poroshenko was elected, the
обязанности потом избрали Порошенко
question is, how did it happen that
вопрос как так получилось что у вас вот
these people were not locals, but citizens of the
эти люди были не местные а граждане
Russian Federation,
Российской Федерации
and Turchynov, he's a local, he's from Kyiv, a
а Турчинов он местный он из Киева
local Ukrainian, yes, so what, a
местный украинец да
citizen of Ukraine, no,
ну и что ну так гражданин Украины нет
wait, how is he a Ukrainian, he's from Russia,
подожди как он украинец он этот с России
Beard with Look, look,
бородай с Смотри смотри вот секунду
good for a second, wait again, look, I
хороший подожди ещё раз смотри я
said it right, look, they came to you
правильно сказал смотри у вас приехали
some people from Russia created the
какие-то люди из России и создали вам
DPR for you Borodai yes
ДНР бородай да
Strelkov Antyufeev and so on yeah yeah yeah so
Стрелков Антюфеев и так дальше
look how so you
ну смотри как так вот ты мне вопрос
asked me a question Ukrainian Russian again I say so that he doesn't
задал украинец русский опять я говорю
run away look if you have
чтобы далеко не убежал смотри если у вас
Russia now well a Russian lives in Kyiv who is he
сейчас россия ну русский живёт в Киеве
Ukrainian or Russian if look
он кто украинец или русский если смотри
we are not talking about nationality he
мы же говорим не про национальность он
can be Jewish but a citizen of
хоть евреем может быть но гражданин
Ukraine or not a citizen here Zelensky is a Jew
Украины или не гражданин вот Зеленский
but he is a citizen of Ukraine this one
еврей но он гражданин Украины вот у
how the
этого э как этого
hell is this banker who escaped a Jew this one
блин банкира который сбежал еврей этот у
how many civilians does he have who escaped well
него сколько там гражданских кто сбежал
where is he now who escaped
ну где он сейчас находится кто сбежал
how how is he now now now I'll
как как же его сейчас сейчас сейчас
remember well who promoted this Zelensky of
вспомню ну который этого Зеленского
yours who who well tell me name
вашего продвигал кто кто ну скажи назови
him I don't know who you are talking about he
его я не знаю о ком ты
had a trial yeah I have no idea come on
суд суд у него был ээ понятия не имею
damn well
давай
he is the only Kolomoisky well
блин ну он единственный коломойский вот
he is a citizen of Ukraine sco not so
ну он гражданин Украины ско не так а
how many citizens does he have yeah look but he is a
сколько у него граждан да смотри но он
citizen of Ukraine the most important thing is that he is a citizen of Ukraine
гражданин Украины самое главное что он
even others but he is a
гражданин Украины даже другие но он
citizen of Ukraine look you have some
гражданин Украины смотри у вас какие-то
people citizens arrived No  look
люди приехали граждане Нет смотри
citizens of another country who
граждане другой страны которые да не
were not citizens of Ukraine were not residents of
были гражданами Украины не были жителями
Donetsk region residents of Donbass yes
Донецкой области жителями Донбасса да
how did it happen that the people of
как так получилось что восстал народ
Donbass rebelled yes but
Донбасса да но из руководствующего
none of the leadership was from Donbass everyone
состава никого не было из Донбасса все
was from Russia
были из России
yes how should I know well well you are a resident of
да откуда я знаю ну ну ты ж ты житель
Donbass you went to the referendum of course the
Донбасса ты на референдум ходил конечно
question: and who organized the referendum for you
вопрос: а кто вам организовал референдум
well it all started with Gubarev Gubarev on
ну начиналось всё с Губарева губарев на
Who organized your Maidan
Кто у вас организовал майдан давай
come on wait again look look look for
подожди ещё раз смотри смотри у вас
you look for you Maidan is Maidan is a
смотри у вас майдан - это майдан это
rally yes for us for example no no look look
митинг да у нас например нет нет смотри
we had the Verkhovna Rada yes
смотри у нас была Верховная Рада да
officially elected people by all
официально избранные люди всеми
citizens of Ukraine you had the Donetsk
гражданами Украины у вас был Донецкий
Regional Council and the Donetsk City
областной совет и Донецкий городской
Council yes people elected by all residents of
совет да люди избранные всеми жителями
Donbass neither the Donetsk Regional Council nor the
Донбасса ни Донецкий областной совет ни
Donetsk City Council made
Донецкий городской совет не принимал
any decisions about referendums
никаких решений про референдумы
proclaiming the DPR who proclaimed the DPR I do
провозглашение ДНР кто провозгласил ДНР
n't know tell me well how look
не знаю расскажи ну как смотри вот
when Ukraine fell apart  Soviet
Украину когда разваливался Советский
Union Ukraine was proclaimed by the Verkhovna
Союз Украину провозгласила Верховная
Rada of Ukraine UrsR yes, the signature is the
Рада Украины УрсР да подпись стоит
head of the Verkhovna Rada Kravchuk,
голова Верховной Рады Кравчук
the question is who and when proclaimed the
вопрос так а кто и когда провозгласил
DPR when your DPR appeared what
ДНР когда появилась ваше ДНР какого
date
числа
look, you understand that there is some
смотри понимаешь что тут какая
cause-and-effect relationship here it doesnt matter
причиннаследственная связь неважно там
when you have Independence Day not
это когда у вас день независимость не
when Independence Day look
когда день независимости вот смотри
Ukraine was born on August 24,
Украина родилась 24 августа девяносто
1991, everything was Independence Day
первого года всё день независимости
when you have Independence Day in the DPR when did
когда у вас в ДНР день независимости
you proclaim independence
когда вы провозгласили независимость
tell me are you a blogger or not I am a blogger yes so
скажи ты блогер или нет я блогер да так
tell me when is your Independence Day so
скажи когда у вас день независимости так
why cant you listen I thought it was
а что ты слушать не умеешь я думал это
just everything So tell me I want to hear from
просто всё Так скажи я хочу услышать от
you Independence Day of the DPR when
тебя день независимости ДНР когда
when is Independence Day of the
когда День независимости
DPR well, you celebrate a young
ДНРА ну вы же празднуете молодая
republic every year should celebrate
республика каждый год должна праздновать
Independence Day in May we celebrate the
День независимости мая празднуем
DPR each country has an
ДНР у каж у каждой страны есть День
Independence Day when it was created yes
независимости когда она создалась да
when was the DPR created was yours when well
когда создана ДНР была ваша когда ну
tell me
скажи
yes you dont see youre running away youre running away
да не видишь ты убегаешь ты убегаешь
because you dont know you dont have
потому что ты не знаешь у вас нету дня
Independence Day when did you get  well no
независимости когда вы получили ну не
need it's a day regardless well when on
надо это день независимо ну когда в
what day look here were you
какой день смотри вот были были вы
part of Ukraine on what day did you become the DPR
частью Украины в какой день вы стали ДНР
just tell me come on a minute you
просто назови мне давай минуту ты
talk then a minute I don't you answer the
говоришь потом минуту я нет ты отвечаешь
question and then you ask a question
на вопрос и тогда ты задаёшь
here you run away because you do
вопроешь вот ты убегаешь потому что ты
n't answer the question tell me some
не отвечаешь на вопрос сказать какой-то
I tell you yes I give you my word answer tell me the
я тебе да Я тебе даю слово ответь скажи
date of the formation of the DPR come on and how many
дата образования ДНР давай а сколько у
subscribers do you have the date of the formation of the DPR
тебя подписчиков дата образования ДНР ты
don't cut yourself off you'll run away now
не срезайся ты сейчас убежишь
if you don't tell me I
если ты мне не будешь говорить я тебе
give you the right to
даю право
answer the date of independence of the DPR answer
ответить дата независимости ДНР отвечай
and ask your question everything is fair
и задавай свой вопрос всё честно
DPR no already now now this is Russia
днр нет уже сейчас сейчас это Россия
when is your Independence Day when was the
когда у вас День независимости когда
DPR created answer I do
было создано ДНР отвечай
n't know well come on look come on look on Google
не знаю а ну поищи давай поищи в Гугле
why am I interested in this come on we'll
зачем мне это интере давай мы сейчас
figure it out now who and when created it I'm
разберёмся кто и когда её создал мне
interested I finally met a living DPR you
интересно я живого ДНР встретил
understand I can now
наконец-то понимаешь я сейчас могу всем
show all the viewers of Ukraine how the
зрителям Украины показать как
DPR was created come on come on what is it for come on
создавалась ДНР давай давай для чего это
find out when  your state was
давай найди ну когда твоё государство
created listen you ukrainian pi went to
создалось слушай ты украин пи пошёл
search run come on come on google when
искать бегом давай давай погуглил когда
your DPR will freeze poor guy come on damn come on
твой ДНР зависошь бедолага
google come on come on
давай капец давай гугли давай давай
talk when your DPR appeared I
давай говори когда твой ДНР появился я
drove you normally around Yes with your face
тебя нормально повозил по Да твоим лицом
yes and now you leave from here like that they all
да а теперь идёшь отсюда вот так они все
yes about I don't know I don't know because
да о не знаю не знаю не знаю потому что
when you start asking them serious
когда начинаете им задавать серьёзные
questions yes it turns out some
вопросы да оказывается там какие-то
Russians came there made them DPR and that's it we go we
россияне пришли сделали им ДНРУ и всё
go further
так едем едем дальше
hello
здравствуйте
from Moldova
из Молдовы
no Samara no and what do you communicate well
нет Самара нет а чем общаетесь
and at once it happens in the weather will be
ну а разом бывает в погоде
in the weather will be about the situation will be about the
будет в погоде будет о ситуации будет о
past
прошлом
cool about the past
прикольно о прошлом
interesting let's try history are you
интересном давайте попробуем историей
interested in well there
интересуетесь
is such a thing cool can you tell
ну есть такое прикольно можете сказать
when the state of Russia was formed
когда образовалось государство России
specifically Russia as a whole or the Russian
конкретно Россия в целом или Российская
Federation Russian
Федерация
Federation well the state in which
российская Федерация ну государство в
you live well the Russian
котором вы живёте ну Российская
Federation was formed in 1991
Федерация образовалась в 1991 году
super that is you have a young state
супер то есть у вас молодое государство
yes
да
republic yes I understand
республи да понял
exactly the state yes country  quite
именно государство да страна достаточно
ancient relatively more precisely in the sense of the
древня относительно точнее в смысле
country relatively ancient that is since
страна относительно древняя то есть с
ninety-one how ancient it is
девяносто первого года как она древняя
not exactly this state that is a
не именно это государство то есть
specific power form of government
конкретная власть форма правления
administration specific
администрация конкретная
and this is a state but as a country
и это государство а как страна
quite a long time ago and what is a country
достаточно давно а что такое страна
then if not a state
тогда если не государство
country well there is if a difference country that is
страна ну есть если отличие страна то
askar more general precisely
есть аскаром более общая именно
historical
историческая
extent community that is people well
протяжённость общность то есть народа ну
historical extent that is you
историческая протяжённость то есть вы
mean that you this is the Mongol
это имеете в виду что вы это монгольская
Empire yes that is if we speak as a
империя да то есть если говорить как
state then we can separately distinguish the
государство то можем отдельно выделить
Russian Federation Russian
Российскую Федерацию Российскую
Republic state Russian
республику государство Российское
Russian Empire if we speak as a
Российскую империю если говорить как о
state if we speak as a country
государстве если говорить как о стране
these are different these are different states yes well
это разные это разные государства да
yes if we speak as a country then we
нуну да если говорить как о стране то мы
take together about Russia as a country then
воедино берём о России как о стране то
we take the Russian Federation republic
мы берём Российскую Федерацию республику
empire and military dictatorship so stop stop
империю и военную диктатуру так стоп
stop and where does your country
стоп стоп а откуда ваша страна
begin then from what year
начинается тогда с какого года
if we speak specifically about the modern
если говорить именно о современном
name of Russia then the proclamation of the
названии России то попроглашения Петром
Russian Empire by Peter I if we take the
Iм Российской империи если именно брать
modern name literally the word
современное название буквально слово
Russia if we speak specifically as about  Rus
Россия если говорить именно как о Руси
about unification by the Moscow principality then
об объединении княжеством московским то
earlier earlier so what does Rus and the
раньше пораньше так причём Русь и
Moscow principality have to do with some different
Княжество Московское какие-то разные
things the
вещи
Moscow principality is one of the
княжество Московское одна из
components of Rus not this principality
составляющей Руси не это княжество
that was part of Rus like yes yes it was
которое входило в Русь типа да да было
controlled by Rus what does it have to do with it but the
подконтрольно Руси причём тут но
Moscow principality is not Rus
княжество Московское это не есть Русь
it's the same as Tajikistan was part of the
это всё равно что Таджикистан входил в
USSR and now Tajikistan will say that it is the
СССР и теперь Таджикистан будет говорить
USSR true
что он и есть СССР правда
yes no the problem is that when we
да не проблема в том что когда мы
talk about principalities then this is a period of
говорим о княжествах то это период
fragmentation once again
раздробленности
that it is fragmented don't look you this is
ещё раз что раздроблен не смотри ты это
already Novgorod Rus Moscow Rus what Novgorod
уже Новгородская Русь Московская Русь
stop stop stop where is
какой Новгородсй стоп стоп стоп где
what Novgorod Rus what are you Petrosyan
какая Новгородская Русь ты что Петросян
Novgorod Muscovite Rus show me
новгородскай Московская Русь покажи
somewhere where it is written Muscovite Rus
где-то хоть чтобы было написано
or Novgorod Rus what are you a
московская Русь или Новгородская Русь ты
joker Muscovite Rus part of Rus
что приколист московская Русь часть Руси
show me where it was Novgorod Rus
покажи где это была новгородская Русь
this is written Novgorod Rus
такое написано новгородская Русь
come on in Novgorod sir the Great
давай ис в Новгороде господин Великий
Novgorod stop stop stop where are you
Новгород стоп стоп стоп где ты такое
reading this Novgorod Rus or
читаешь новгородская Русь или там
Muscovite Rus where did you read
Московская Русь это где ты прочитал
when there was such a state Muscovite
когда было такое государство Московская
Rus
Русь
well the Principality of Moscow wait stop stop
ну княжество Московское подожди стоп
you said Muscovite Rus
стоп ты сказал Московская Русь
no Principality of Moscow or Muscovite
нет княжество Московское или Московская
Rus
Русь
these are like closer concepts no so
это как более близкие понятие нет так
wait and Ryazan Rus was well that
подожди а Рязанская Русь была
is what if it was I don't know
ну то есть кака если было не знаю было
if it was like a separate principality if it was then it
ли как отдельно княжество если была то
was the Principality of Rednya then it was Ryazan
было княжество Редня то была Рязанская
Rus yes yes you can call it and Murom Rus
Русь да да можно и называть а Муромская
was Murmansk Muroms Muromskaya
Русь была Мурманск муромс муромская
Muromskaya Rus
муромская Русь
well if there was a principality in Sta Rus then it is
ну если было княжество в Ста Руси то
quite like one of the spare parts and Tver
вполне как одна из запчастей а Тверская
Rus was yes one of the contenders for the
Русь была да один из претендентов на
unification of all the principalities Tver
объединение всех княжеств Русь тверская
Rus I understand it was called Tver
Русь понял она так и называлась тверская
Rus well the Principality of Tver wait
Русь да ну княжество Тверское подожди
so the Principality of Tver or Tverskaya Rus
так княжество Тверское или Тверская Русь
these are like close concepts no no these are
это как близкие понятия нет нет это
completely different concepts well never in life
вообще разные понятия ну никогда в жизни
no principality, neither Moscow nor
никакое княжество ни московское ни
Tver, called itself Muscovite
Тверское не называло себя Московская
Rus Tver Rus and so on, truth be told
Русь Тверская Русь и так дальше правда
[music] I
[музыка]
can't say for sure here, to be honest,
тут не могу точно сказать честно говоря
yes, definitely, find somewhere where they
да точно найди вот хоть где-то чтобы они
called themselves Muscovite, well,
называли себя московская хорошо
Muscovite
московская
Rus Muscovite Rus is a
Русь московская Русь
historical historiogeographical
исторический историогеографический
term that can be used to denote
термин которым могут обозначаться
historical states, that is,
исторические государства состои то есть
look, that is, a term that
смотри то есть термин который
modern Russian historians
современные историки российские
came up with
придумали
no from Wikipedia from a foreign source
нет с Википедии с иностранного источника
no no no no show me again where
нет нет нет нет ещё раз покажи мне где
this state Muscovite Rus is, this is a
это государство Московская Русь это вот
modern term, yes, which your
современный термин да который ваши
historians are trying to come up with for themselves there
историки себе пробуют придумать там
Muscovite
Московская
Rus is a
Русь
moscographic term that can be used to
москографический термин которым могут
denote historical
могут обозначать исторические
states, yes, that is, that is,
государство могут да то есть то есть
historians, historians can designate,
историки вот историки могут обозначать
that is, there was no state Muscovite
то есть никакого государства Московская
Rus with such a name, truth be told, at the
Русь не было с таким названием правда
beginning of its entire existence
вот в начале целого существования
Muscovite Rus intersects
Московская Русь пересекается
Vladimir Rus once again, once again,
Владимирская Русь ещё раз ещё
show me at least one
раз покажи мне хоть одно документ
historical document that contains the phrase
исторический да в котором есть фраза
Muscovite
Московская
Rus well, I can't say spontaneously,
Русь ну так не могу спонтанно сказать
more precisely,
точнее
show me, I'll be
показать буду
honest well  find find it's simple if there
честен ну найди найди это ж просто если
was Muscovite Rus a state yes
была Московская Русь государство да
find there or there a coin a term that
найди там или там монета термин который
denotes states once again once again
обозначает государства ещё раз ещё раз
this is a term that now one of you
это термин который сейчас кто-то из вас
will come up with yes I can say that it was
придумает да я могу сказать что была
shorter for example there was Ladoga Rus there was
короче например там Ладожская Русь была
Chechen Rus Buryat Rus yes
Чеченская Русь Бурятская Русь да что
anything can be come up with now but show
угодно можно придумать сейчас но покажи
me in those times so that the people who
мне в те времена чтобы люди которые там
lived there called themselves Muscovite Rus yes
жили называли себя Московская Русь да
so that the prince would say that I am the prince of Muscovite
чтоб князь говорил что я князь
Rus that I am the prince of Tver
Московской Руси что я князь Тверской
Rus
Руси
show the
покажи
archive to the archive of Russia
архив на архив России
so well
так
yes a modern term
ну да современный термин
that is such a sovereign that is such a
то есть такого государ то есть такого
state as Muscovite Rus did not exist
государства как Московская Русь не было
from the name true as a state no
от названия правда как государство нет
this is a term to denote a period ki
это термин для обозначения периода ки
no look and Kievan Rus did not exist yes there was
нет смотри и Киевская Русь не было да
simply Rus it was simply Rus it was
была просто Русь была просто Русь она
one yes with the center in Kyiv no
была одна да с центром в Киеве никаких
other Rus existed well the center
других Русей не существовало ну центр
changed from time to time never when from
менялся время от времени никогда когда с
Kyiv where did the center of Rus change and the center
Киева куда поменялся центр Руси а центр
was it turns out
был получается
in what in what year tell me in what year
в каком в каком году скажи в каком году
from Kyiv the center was moved somewhere to another
с Киева перенесли центр куда-то в другое
place of Rus
место Руси
not from Kyiv  moved no no look where
не с В Киев перенесли нене смотри откуда
Kyiv was the center of Rus yes if
вот Киев был центром Руси да если
Muscovite Rus there when from Kievo to
Московская Русь там когда с Киево в
Moscow the center of
Москву перенесли центр
Rus
Руси
switched yeah that's
переключился угу
all the trashing of these
всё вот и всё разнос этих
pseudo-historians like subscribe comment
псевдоисториков лайк подписка коммент вы
where are you from no where from where are you from we are
откуда
from another
ну ни откуда откуда вы мы с другого
place I am from the city of Khmelnitsky and you are
места я из города Хмельницкий а вы
from Khmelniki we are from the city of Tikhoretsky
откуда хмельнико мы из города Тихорецкий
like the train will leave for Tikhoretskaya it
типа на Тихорецкую состав отправится это
seems to be Krasnodar Krai somewhere or
вроде Краснодарский край где-то или
Stavropol
Ставропольский
yes yes yes that's exactly what you talk about
да да да именно так о чём общаетесь
everyone knows Vysotsky's song yes yes
песню Высоцкого все знают да да
what do you talk about we talk in principle
о чём общаетесь мы общаемся в принципе
on any topic well no matter how much we don't
на любые темы ну как сильно не
go into detail somewhere we just talk to
вглубляемся куда-то просто общаемся с
people yes it's cool with whom we work
людьми да прикольно с кем работаем е
if we
если
work and this is very important
работаем а это очень важно
yes yes m well
да да м
I can't tell who I work for
ну я не могу сообщить кем я работаю
why
почему
because I am in the structures
потому что я в структурах
no
нет
and who three letters power MVD FSB
а кто три буквы власть МВД ФСБ
that's what I guessed cool
вот угадал прикольно
subordination personally Vladimir Vladimirovich
подчинение лично Владимир Владимирович
Putin cool yes well yes yes and I am a komba A
Путин прикольно да ну да да а а я комба
I and this kombaner is sitting next to just an
А я а это комбанёр рядом сидит просто
ordinary kombaner  Kombaner and everything also
обычный комбанёр комбанёр и всё тоже
personally obeys Putin yes why not why doesn't
лично Путину подчиняется да почему нет
he obey Putin doesn't
зачем он Путину не подчиняется не
obey well you can see from his face
подчиняется ну у него по лицу видно
that he also obeys Putin
прямо что он тоже Путину подчиняется
and who do you obey I don't
а вы кому подчиняетесь я никому не
obey anyone I am a free man
подчиняюсь я вольный человек
well you have a flag behind your back you are sitting this is the
ну у вас за спиной флаг вы сидите это
flag of my country and what like in order to
флаг моей страны и что типа для того
have a flag on your part you have to
чтобы иметь флаг с твоей стороны надо
obey someone
кому-то подчиняться
no well you really support I see we
нет ну вы очень топите я смотрю за это
all support this thing well well and why are
дело всё топим да
you supporting me
ну вот а за что вы топите
I support the Russians
я русских
yeah and why with
ага а зачем
facts this is funny and what are the downsides
фактами это весело а какие минусы
oh come on and wait and why are you supporting me at all
о давай а подождите а за что вы вообще
for your country
топите вот за свою страну
and what did Russia do to you wrong that you
а что вам Россия сделала не так что вы
started supporting Ukraine well just yes I'll
начали топить за Украину ну просто Да
explain we are returning the historical lands of
объясню мы возвращаем исторические земли
Kievan Rus Moscow was created by the Kiev
Киевской Руси москву создал кто киевский
prince Yuri Dolgoruky therefore Moscow is a
князь Юрий Долгорукий поэтому Москва -
Kiev city it should obey
это киевский город он должен подчиняться
Kyiv that's all Kyiv was the capital of
Киеву вот и всё киев был стольный
Krai Rus that's right well look Kyiv
краивская Русь правильно ну смотри Киев
yes while the Mongols yes not Ukrainian not
да пока монголы да не украинская не
Ukrainian so we want yes we want to
украинская так мы хотим да мы хотим
return subordination to Kyiv  all these cities
вернуть подчинение Киеву все это города
and rename Ukraine to Rus that's all
и переименовать Украину в Русь вот и всё
back this will not happen you understand it will happen
назад такого не будет понимаешь будет
because look we yes together with
будет потому что смотри мы да вместе с
our brothers Anglo-Saxons yes we are
нашими братьями англосаксами да
returning our historical lands to ourselves there
возвращаем себе наши исторические земли
was never a Ukrainian Rus the sky is
так не было никогда украинской Руси небо
right that's how Lenin came up with it came up with
правильно так придумал ленин придумал
Ukraine Lenin came up with it you know that's
Украину ленин придумал ты же знаешь вот
exactly of course yes and since then Lenin
именно конечно да и с тех пор Ленин
came up with it for what because there was a
придумал для чего потому что была
Russian Empire which was ruled by
Российская империя которой правили немцы
some Germans Catherine and everything there Elizabeths
какие-то екатерины и всё там елизаветы
they were Germans yes not Russians Germans
они нем немки были да не русские немцы
never Russians wrong wait well
никогда русские неправильно подожди ну
Tsarina Elizabeth Catherine they were Germans
царица Елизавета Екатерина они немки
seriously with Russian names Germans were yes
серьёзно с русскими именами немки были
so look she was I'll tell you now
да так посмотри она была я тебе сейчас
look what she was called they
скажу смотри как она называлась это её
renamed her here she is Anhaltzer
переименовали вот она ангальцербская
some kind of there now
какая-то там сейчас
Katerina now
катерина сейчас
look
смотри
so interesting right yes he
так интересно прямо да у него грамотно
speaks competently here is Catherine II yes she is
разговори вот Екатерина II да она же
Catherine II Alekseevna or Catherine the
Екатерина II Алексеевна или Екатерина
Great at birth her name was Sophia
Великая при рождении её имя София
Augusta  Frederica of
Августа Фредерика
Anhaltzerb she is German not so history well
Ангальцербская она немка не так истори а
open up please [ __ ] wonder
ну открой пожалуйста [__] интересно а
well open up I am not lying I am a
ну открой я же не обманываю я
history teacher maybe it is difficult I do
преподаватель истории возможно сложно
not know history I find it difficult to argue such
историю не знаю я сложно спорить такой
history I do not know maybe I do not want to
истории я не знаю возможно я не хочу
argue now she she was born in the state
спорить сейчас она она родилась в штате
not in
не в
Prussia look now on Google
Прусии посмотри сейчас на Гугле
Catherine IIra there it is no question the
екатерина IIра там это ж базара нет
second former imperialist all-Russian well well
вторая бывшая империатист всероссийская
read
ну ну читай
here Wikipedia
вот Википедия
aizimri niece of the Swedish king
айзимри племица шведского
ttt here is the future daughter of the prince no
королят ттт вот будущий дочери княза не
higher higher than the niece of the Swedish
выше выше чем племянница шведского
king above from the very beginning in bold
короля выше с самого начала жирными
letters it is written in Wikipedia Catherine
буквами написано в Википедии Екатерина
II Alekseyevna read
II алексеевна читай
above here you opened Wikipedia
выше вот ты Википедию открыл
Yes yes yes come on read in bold bold at the top it is
Да да да давай читай жирным жирным
written Catherine II Catherine
вверху написано екатерина II екатерина
II Alekseyevna Catherine the Great
II алексеевна Екатерина Великая
ne Sophia Augusta Frederica of
урождённая софия Августа фредерика
Anhalt Zerboska
Ангальт Цербоская
thank you and look in German how she
спасибо и вон по-немецки как она
she is called a German but
называется она немка была
look it says German yes
а вот смотри написано немецкий язык да
German but wait let's
немецкий ано подожди а давай снизу
read from below wait look being the daughter of
прочитаем подожди смотри будучи дочерью
Prince Anhalt of Serbia Catherine
князя Ангальд Сербовского Екатерина
Anhalt of Serbia yes it is a German German he
ангальт Сербского да это немца немца он
was her father her father but she married the
был её отец её отец но она вышла замуж
third as a result of a court
третьего в результате дворского
coup against her husband Peter
переворота против своего мужа Петра
II gender that under imperfect
II пола что при невосовершенства
circumstances it is possible he was killed yes she
обстоятельствах возможно он был убит да
ascended to the throne following a precedent
она зашла на престол след преценденту
look so Peter everything is correct
посмотри так Пётр всё правильно
correct now look Peter II click he was
правильно теперь смотри Пётр II нажми он
also he was German look at birth
же тоже был он немец смотри при рождении
Karl Peter Ulrich her husband well look
Карл Пётр Ульрих её муж ну посмотри вот
there where it says Peter click Peter i
там где написано Петра вот нажми Пётр i
look wait wait you see if
смотри стой подожди стой понимаешь если
they were of heavenly origin but they
они были небеского происхождения но они
went for Rus' again once again
же за Русь пошли ещё ещё раз ещё раз
look her husband gave their power to the husband
смотри её муждали свою власть муж
whom she killed no it is a blogger I will
которого убила нет это же блогер я тебе
look for you again on Google her husband Peter II
ещё раз на Гугле смотри её муж Пётр II
blogger yes take Peter II her husband take
блогер да возьми Пётр II её муж возьми
Wikipedia  Peter II well take it read it
Википедии пётр II ну возьми прочитай его
well really Peter II yes Peter II her husband
ну реально петра II да петро II её муж
well why should I read it wait so he is also
ну а зачем мне читать стой так он тоже
German
немец
yes wait well the fact is the fact look
да стой ну а факт факт посмотри вот
right now look Peter II yes the arrival is
прямо сейчас смотри пётр II да приждение
good Peter II Karl Peter Ulrich yes
хорошо пётр II карл Пётр Ульрих да
German yes he was born in the city of Kiel
немецкий да родился в городе Киль
that's good and Peter I of Russia Russian
вот хорошо а Пётр I Росси русский ещё
read it again
раз прочитай
Peter I Russian Peter I was Dutch
пётр I русский пётр I голландец был
look let's figure it out with Peter II now the
посмотри вот давай сейчас с Петром II
Germans you know Russia was
разберёмся немцы понимаешь России
ruled by the Germans wait wait wait wait
правили немцы подожди стой стой стой
wait Germans Germans yes
стой немцы немцы да
yes and
да и
everything works out then look then the
всё получается потом смотри потом правил
Jew Lenin ruled then the Georgian Stalin
еврей Ленин потом правил грузин Сталин
ruled then the Ukrainians ruled Khrushchev the former
потом правили украинцы Хрущёв прежний
Lenin was a Jew Lenin was a Jew yes
Ленин был евреем ленин еврей был да
Ulyanov was a Jew yes no his dad is
ульянов был евреем да у не у него папа
Chuvash Ulyanov and his mother Blank yes it is he
чуваш Ульянов а мама Бланк да это он
Ulyanov or a Jew he is on his mother's side Blank the Jews on his
Ульянов или еврей он по маме бланк евреи
mother's side they think his mother is Jewish
по маме считают у него мама еврейка
halakhic Jew and dad is a Chuvash from
галахическая еврейка а папа чуваш из
Ulyanovsk from Simbirsk that's all then
Ульяновска из Симбирска вот и всё потом
look Stalin Georgian then Khrushchev
смотри Сталин грузин потом Хрущёв
Brezhnev Ukrainians and then everything Gorbachev
Брежневы украинцы да потом всё Горбачу
in short it turns out that the Russians only had
короче получается у русских только
Yeltsin their own Ukraine arose in
Ельцин появился свой украина возникла в
ninety-one right
девяносто первом году правильно потому
because Lenin created it yes he decided yes
что Ленин создал её да он с он решил да
because Lenin said: "Look they
потому что Ленин сказал: "Смотри они не
can't be what can't be Ukrainian?"   Explain I'll
могут быть что не может быть украинцем?"
explain look Lenin killed a
Объясни объясню смотри Ленин убил
German he was not Ukrainian Lenin overthrew the
немецкого не был украинцем ленин скинул
German Tsar he was from the German dynasty
немецкого царя же был из династии немцев
yes these Romanovs uh killed him and said
да вот эти Романовы ээ убил его и сказал
that we should restore Rus' with the
что мы должны восстановить Русь с
center in Kyiv that's why he invented
центром в Киеве поэтому он придумал
Ukraine and then so that Ukraine would
Украину да и дальше чтобы Украина
gather all the rest of the lands of Rus' that's
собирала остальные все земли Руси вот и
all well so Yelts could not be Ukrainian
всё ну так Ельца не мог быть украинцем
Yeltsin could not Yeltsin Russian here Yeltsin was the
ельцин не мог бы ельцин русский вот
first Russian he was even visible
Ельцин первый русский он был даже видно
on him wait Catherine the first then that
было по нему стой екатерина первая тогда
is Catherine the first who was she
то есть Екатерина первая кто она была
look who she is anyway well
посмотри кто она вообще
let me switch to myself about
такая ну давай я переключусь на себя о
Catherine I who created Catherine
Екатерина I которая создала Екатерина
Andar
Андар
city I have no idea who
город я понятия не имею кто такая
Catherine I is why I need her I know
Екатерина I зачем она мне нужна я знаю
Catherine II she was the most important thing
Екатерину II она была самое главное
no Catherine well Catherine I I
нет Екатерина хорошо екатерина Iвая
read
читаю
Polish from birth Marta Elena
полячка от рождения Марта елена
Skavroskaya read Catherine I read
Скавроская прочитай екатерина I прочитай
Polish prokipedia read yes read
полячка прокипедию прочитай да прочитай
from Wikipedia I will read she she she she
из Википедии я прочитаю она она она она
created Ekaterinar  that's right
же создала Екатеринар правильно это
she's a Pole she's a Pole that means Yekaterindar
полячка она полячка значит Екатериндар
Polish Krasnodar Polish no no it's
польский краснодар польский да
not Polish she created for
нет он не польский она создала для
Russians look again I read
русских вот смотри ещё раз я читаю
Catherine I of March Samuilovna Skavroskaya
екатерина I марта Самуиловна Скавроская
in marriage his last name was Kruzy yes after
в браке его фамилия Крузы была да после
adopting Orthodoxy she already became
принятия православия она уже стала
Alekseyevna like that Crowned everything
Алексеевна типа вот так Коронована всё
she's a Pole really a Pole but where is she
она полячка реально полячка а где она
what was she born in Pole yes she was born yes she was
что она родилась в поляке да она
born in Sweden yes she was
родилась да родилась в Швеции да
born in the kingdom of Sweden well
родилась в королевстве Швеции
and the fact is a fact a fact a person a person
ну а факт факт факт факт человек человек
created a city right she look she's a
создал город правильно она смотри она
Swedish freak yes a Pole created for you for you for
шведская уродженка да полячка создала
Yekaterinodar even the Poles
вам вам вам Екатеринодар даже поляки
created you yourselves couldn't create at all wait wait wait it
создали вы сами не могли создать вообще
turns out you could
получается вы
n't stand it either not a
тоже не выдержали
Pole but a Pole so that's when you
не полячка а полька так вот да когда
start digging all these Russians Russians
начинаешь копать все эти русские русские
they are Swedes
они шведы
Poles
поляки
Germans and these just enlighten yourself look
немцы а эти аж просветись посмотри
look he can't even read by
посмотри он даже прочитать не может по
syllables Mangaltserbskaya yes like subscribe
слогам мангальцербская да лайк подписка
comment for enlightenment of Russian
коммент за просвещение российского
hello
здравствуйте
good night where are you from
доброй ночи вы откуда
Tamansky Peninsula is
таманскимский полуостров
cool Cossack region
прикольно казачий край
yes absolutely right from Timryuk my
да совершенно верно из Тимрюка у меня
dad is from
батя родом
even
даже
so I am also from Timryuksky district
так я вот тоже с Тимрюкцского района
damn how round the world is yes yes in fact it is
блин как мир круглый да да на самом деле
cool and what do you communicate with
прикольно а чем общаетесь
yes I don't know you are adults I decided to
да не знаю вы взрослые я решил так
just find out what people do
просто чем люди занимаются узнать
listen what do you think
слушайте как считаете
why did they make this war so that Slavs would
зачем сделали вот эту войну чтобы
kill Slavs
убивали славяне славян
well you know everyone has their own truth and yes
ну вы знаете у каждого своя правда и да
I want to listen to your truth well
я же вашу правду хочу послушать
let's hear my truth came about from the fact that
ну давайте моя правда сложилась с того
well what they
что ну то что нам
tell us and they told us that why Crimea
говорят а нам сказали что почему Крым
joined let's say yes to Russia
присоединился допустим да к России
because I heard Pavel Muraev and then
что я слышал Павла Мураева и потом
our media said that
сказали наши уже СМИ что
Ukraine decided to give up its fleet and to NATO
Украина решила отдать флот а под НАТО
uh and we took Crimea and Donbass Lugansk
ээ и Крым мы забрали а Донбасс Луганск
well as they tell us and as if I also
ну как нам говорят и как бы я тоже
probably most likely believe in this
наверное скорее всего в это и
not that
верю не что там живут
Russian-speaking people live there and you have
русскоязычные и у вас там начался в
some kind of Nazism started there in Ukraine in Kyiv and
Украине какой-то нацизм там в Киеве и
torchlight processions there back and forth and that's where it
факельные шествия там туда-сюда и вот с
all started
этого всё и началось
I don't understand wait Russian-speaking people for
я что не понимаю подожди русскоязычные
example live in Cuba  Spanish speakers
вот например на Кубе живут испаноязычные
live in Chile Spanish speakers yes Spanish speakers live in Mexico
в Чили живут испаноязычные да в Мексике
what does Spain
испаноязычные какое отношение Испания
have to do with some Spanish speakers in these
имеет к каким-то испаноязычным в этих
countries but their rights are not infringed
странах но их не ущемляют их права
so stop let's go to the USA in the USA somewhere around 10% of
так стоп давайте в США в США где-то 10%
Spanish speakers are Hispanooblantos
испаноязычных испанооблантос
yeah yeah and they are the ones who are infringed there are no
угу так и их как раз ущемляют нету и
schools in Spanish here English is spoken
школ на испанском тут английский короче
somehow everything is sort of imposed yeah why does
как-то всё типа насаживают да почему
n't Spain somehow interfere what does it have to do with
Испания как-то не вмешивается это причём
Spanish speakers and Spain well in
тут испаноязычные и Испания ну говорят в
different countries they speak Spanish in different countries they
разных странах на испанском в разных на
speak Russian and what well
русскох говорят и что
okay let's not take this as the
ну давайте ладно не будем это брать
key no no I just want to understand
ключевое нене просто я хочу понять
look for example Austria is a
смотрите вот например Австрия
German-speaking country yeah yeah should the
германо-язычная страна угу да должны ли
Germans well there was already one such Austrian
немцы ну был уже один такой австрийский
artist he just raised this issue
художник он как раз вот этот вопрос
yeah Austria should annex
поднимал да Австрию присоединить к себе
all of South America except Brazil something else
вся Южная Америка кроме Бразилии что-то
small
там ещё одного маленького
Spanish-speaking Mexico Spanish-speaking
испаноязычная мексика испаноязычная
Latin America Spanish-speaking why
Латинская Америка испаноязычная почему
doesn't Spain Why does
Испания не Почему Франция
n't France raise  some kind of protection of the
не поднимает вопрос какие-то защиты
Francophone population there in Africa or
франкофонные населения там Африки или
Guinea
Гвинеи
because it does not infringe or burn
потому что она не ущемляет не сжигает
books Russians do not speak or call for that the
книги русских не говорят не призывают к
French there or Spanish-speaking
тому что французов там или испаноязычных
people and stop stop stop do I
людей а стоп стоп стоп я правильно
understand correctly that in Ukraine they call up
понимаю что в Украине призывают
Russian-speakers well they
русскоязычных так
called up at least in the fourth year and
ну призывали как минимум в четым году а
can you give an example where in Ukraine they
можете сказать пример где в Украине
called up just half of our
призывали просто у нас половина
politicians speak Russian yes let's
политикума говорит на русском языке да
not play fools with you
давайте мы не будем с вами играть в
no no no let's really not
дурачков нене не давайте реально не
play fools you show where
будем играть в дурачков вы покажете где
in Ukraine they called up Russian-speakers who is a
же в Украине призывали русскоязычных кто
Russian soldier for you yeah in the Ukrainian language
российский солдат угу в украинском языке
and pokoiny was centuries and also Shevchenko
да и спокойн веков был да ещё Шевченко
even a soldier these are Russian people not
даже солдат это российские люди не
Russian people this is
российские люди это
Nagulyaku what nagilyaku yes and what who is this who is this
Нагуляку что нагиляку да и что кого это
Russian soldier yes that is the
кого это российского солдата да
entire male population that is
то есть мужское всё население то есть
nagilyakh why male military
нагилях почему мужское военных
occupiers
оккупантов
then there were no so look again
тогда ещё не было так ещё раз смотри
come on look again you say that in
давай ещё раз смотри ты говоришь что в
Russia in Ukraine they killed or called up
Росси в Украине убивали там или призвали
Rulsko-speaking people  yes I can even see that Russia
рульскоязычных да я аж вижу что Россия
destroyed the Russian-speaking city of Bakhmut
уничтожила русскоязычный город Бахмут
70,000 Russian-speaking population Russia
70.000 русскоязычного населения россия
drops aerial bombs FABs on
скидывает авиабомбы Фабы на
Russian-speaking Kharkov Russia bombed
русскоязычный Харьков россия разбомбила
Russian-speaking Mariupol Russia drops bombs on Russian-speaking Odessa so I can't
русскоязычную Одессу так я не могу
understand Russia is protecting Russian-speakers or
понять Россия защищает русскоязычных или
killing I see that
убивает я смотрю что от российского
so many Russian-speakers have died from Russian weapons that it
оружия русскоязычных погибло столько
was even unthinkable so I
сколько немыслимо даже было так я же вам
told you so we started that conversation
и говорил вот мы начали тот разговор
that doesn't need to be started everyone has their own
который не нужно начинать у каждого своя
truth so we are ordinary people we don't
правда так мы ж мы простые люди мы же не
fight we need to now you are
сримся надо вот мне сейчас вот вы мне
telling me that Russians are
сейчас говорите что русские фабами
bombing
бомбят
Russian-speakers with FABs to protect well this is what we are
русскоязычных защищают ну это то что мы
bombing civilians with FABs this is what
бомбим фабами мирное население это с
you wrote down correctly I
ваших слов записано верно правильно мною
read it correctly this is what you are
прочитано это вы так
saying and if in return we have such
говорите а если обратно у нас такая
truth well look if FAP
правда ну смотри если ФАП сегодня
flew today to Sumy region in the city of Sumy
прилетел в Сумскую область в городе Сумы
to a school yard and ra school yes then  it's a
на школьный двор и ра школу да то это
fact if a Russian FAP arrives
факт если российский ФАП прилетает
show me a video video well come on
покажите мне видео видео ну так зайдите
look don't tell these tales yes you
ну смотрите не надо эти басни да вы
say that they killed there and so on
говорите что там убивали и так дальше
it's all lies but you look at the Russian bombs targets
это всё брехня а вот российские бомбы вы
Ukraine hits an
смотрите цели украина поражает в России
oil refinery in Russia right on target
нефтеперерабатывающий завод чётко в цель
Russia hits a nine-story building in Odessa a nine-
россия поражает девятиэтажку в Одессе
story building in Krivoy Rog yes a nine-
девятиэтажку в Кривом Рогу да
story building in Kharkov and so on
девятиэтажку в Харькове и так дальше
civilian targets the city of Bakhmud let's do that the
гражданские цели город Бахмуд давай так
city of Bakhmut well agree it's
хорошо город Бахмут ну согласись он
wiped off the face of the earth no one lives there you
стёрт с лица земли там никто не живёт ты
can check it's elementary true
можешь это проверить элементарно правда
any
любая
village any city has been wiped off the face of the earth
деревня любой город стёрт с лица земли
why is Bakhmut here well
был почему здесь Бахмут
because you wiped it out name me a
ну потому что вы стёрли назовите мне
village that hasn't been wiped off the face of the earth
деревню которая не стёрли с лица земли
name me any village Mariupol wasn't
назовите мне любую деревню мариуполь не
wiped off the face of the earth no yes you wiped a
стёрт был с лица земли нет да вы стёрли
Russian-speaking city off the face of the earth what does
русскоязычный город с лица земли а
Bakhmut have to do with it then what kind of Bakhmut do you have
причём здесь Бахмут тогда что у вас за
for example Bakhmut Mariupol
Бахмут для примера вам Бахмут Мариуполь
I'm telling you yes you wipe it out why are you I
я же говорю да вы стираете почему вы я
just can't  understand look I'm not
просто не могу понять смотри я ж не
arguing I want to understand your thinking the
ссорюсь я хочу понять мышление вашу
truth you wanted to protect
правду вы захотели защитить
Russian speakers and 70,000 Bakhmut to zero
русскоязычных и 70.000 Бахмута под ноль
their houses their Mariupol 700,000
ихние дома их мариуполь 700.000
population well what is the protection and you
населения ну в чём защита а вы мне
tell me uh Bakhmud is behind Mariupol
скажите э Бахмуд находится за Мариуполем
right I understand well he goes outside Mariupol
правильно я понимаю ну он вне Мариуполя
and Mariupol behind Bakht wait
заходит и Мариуполь за Бахтом подожди
wait so I understand first comes
подожди чтобы я понимал первый идёт
Mariupol then comes Bakhmut right
Мариуполь потом идёт Бахмут правильно
depending on where you look if you look from
смотря откуда смотреть если смотреть с
Mariupol then first comes Mariupol then
Мариуполя то первым идёт Мариуполь потом
Bakhmut if from Bakhmut then first comes
Бахмут если с Бахмута то первым идёт
Bakhmut second Mariupol logically in short it does
Бахмут вторым Мариуполь логично короче
n't matter where the Russian army wrote it was
неважно откуда русская армия написала
advancing from Mariupol from different places from
наступала с Мариуполя с разных мест с
different places uh separately to Mariupol and
разных мест ээ отдельно на Мариуполь и
separately to Bakhmut these are different branches
отдельно на Бахмут это разные ветки
why didn't they evacuate people I can't
почему не эвакуировали людей я не могу
understand the Ukrainian government why didn't they
понять украинское правительство почему
evacuate they evacuated people
не не эвакуировали эвакуировало людей
why not everyone if you say there are
почему не всех если вы говорите там
70,000 or something thousands well why is
70.000 сколько-то там тысяч ну почему
everything theirs so right look  their
всё ихний так правильно смотрите ихнее
population yes destroyed you destroyed the
население да уничтожено вы уничтожили
houses of these people why
дома этих людей почему
because it's a war well how that is
потому что это война ну как то есть
wait so war to protect these
подожди так война для защиты этих
Russian speakers I well look I just
русскоязычных я ну смотри я я просто
want to understand these Russian speakers asked:
хочу понять эти русскоязычные просили:
"Come and destroy our houses" well I
"Придите и уничтожьте наши дома" ну не
can't what's the trick the
могу в чём фишка
trick is that they understand why all this is
фишка в том что они понимают для чего
happening and have you seen Mariupol
это всё происходит а вы Мариуполь видели
in general recently
вообще последнее время
yes destroyed I saw rallies in Mariupol
да разрушенный видел митинги в Мариуполе
where is the promised but you haven't seen the
где обещанная же а вы не видели
rebuilt Mariupol no I saw yes a couple of
отстроенный Мариуполь нет видел да пару
five-story buildings were rebuilt and people I saw
пятиэтажек отстроили и люди я видел
rallies in Mariupol yes fresh and even since
митинги в Мариуполе да свежие да ещё с
February 2025 where are the people training
февраля месяца 2025 года где люди трени
where is this promised housing analysis we will
где же это обещанное жильё разбор мы ни
not come to anything you have your own truth
к чему не придём у вас своя правда у
I have my own I have facts and you have lies everything is
меня своя у меня факты а у вас ложь всё
simple why I have lies so why
просто почему у меня ложь так почему
tell me
скажите
how did you protect the residents let's go let's
как вы защитили жителей давайте давайте
go well what let's go here I am
давайте ну а что давайте вот я вот вот
you are running away no you are running away
вы убегае нет вы убегаете
you are running away now from the topic of
убегаете вы сейчас убегаете с темы
Bakhmut it is very bright  illustrates
Бахмута он очень ярко иллюстрирует
tell me how you protected them and from
расскажите как вы защитили их да и от
what
чего
listen to me I often watch the
послушайте меня я вот часто смотрю канал
Freedom channel this is already a Ukrainian channel
Freedom это уже украинский канал
right I don't care about the Freedom channel
правильно мне без разницы канал Freedom
let's talk about Mari about Bakhmut why are you running away they
давай про Мари про Бахмут почему ты
tell look you're running away you're doing it
убегаешь рассказывают смотри ты убегаешь
on purpose you're merging with Bakhmut I do
ты специально ты сливаешься с Бахмута я
n't know anything about Bakhmut what do you want
ничего не знаю про Бахмут что вы хотите
from me no you know that he will destroy
от меня нет ты знаешь что он уничтожит
so tell me just what you how you
так расскажи мне просто что вы как вы
protected these people and from what
защитили этих людей да и от чего
protected the residents of Bakhmut
защитили жителей Бахмута
from the Nazis from you yeah yeah that is if you
от нацистов от вас угу то есть если вы
didn't bomb their city then what would the
не разбомбили ихний город то что бы
Nazis do to the residents of Bakhmut
сделали нацисты с жителями Бахмута
probably mocked them the way they
наверное издевались так как они
mocked them all this time yeah what
издевались всё это время угу что
happened in Mariupol no no so
происходило в Мариуполе не нет так что
wait what about the residents of Bakhmut how the
подожди что с жителями Бахмута как
Nazis mocked the residents of Bakhmut
нацисты издевались над жителями Бахмута
I'm interested and how you protected them from
мне интересно и как вы защитили от
mockery watch the chronicle no
издевательств вы хронику посмотрите
no just tell me how with the residents of
нене просто скажите как с жителями
Bakhmut and your truth once again always yeah
Бахмута а своя правда ещё раз всегда да
yeah I your truth I  he came
да я вашу правду я же пришёл
for That's how they are if you start them with
за Вот так они если их начинаешь
simple facts and simple logic yes
простыми фактами и простой логикой да
they burn and run away because the
они подгорают и убегают потому что
truth is for Ukraine because all these
правда за Украины потому что все эти
fairy tales are about protecting Russian speakers because
сказки защита русскоязычных потому что
someone shouted Nagilyak yes they came to
там кто-то кричал Нагиляку да они пришли
protect the residents of Bakhmut and their city
защитить жителей Бахмута и ихний город
they came to protect the residents of Mariupol
они пришли защитить жителей Мариуполя
more than half a million city and destroyed
более полумиллионы город и уничтожили
it and its residents
его и его жителей
what is the protection from
в чём защита от
whom under the evil Nazis the residents of Mariupol
кого при злых нацистах жители Мариуполя
and Bakhmut lived normally went to
и Бахмута жили нормально ходили на
work to school got married studied spoke
работу в школу женились учились
Russian
разговаривали на русском
Russia came and
языке пришла Россия и всех
killed everyone like subscribe comment and send
убила лайк подписка коммент и скиньте
this video to your friends hello hello hello
это видео знаёмым здравствуйте
I am from the city of
здравствуйте здравствуйте я из города
Khmelnitsky where are you from the city of
Хмельницкий вы откуда из города
St. Petersburg what do you talk about
Санкт-Петербург о чём общаетесь
differently interesting I Yes I watched a
по-разному интересно я Да я смотрел
video from St. Petersburg yesterday it was
видео из Санкт-Петербурга вчера было
Uraza Bayram
Ураза Байрам
and these huge
и вот эти огромные
as if number of Muslims on the
как бы количество мусульман на
street and I wonder can you Yes you can Yes
улице и вот мне интересно можете Да
I wonder can you
умечате да мне интересно
remember when there was at least an
можете вспомнить когда был хотя бы
approximate mass action of
приблизительный по массовости акция
Russians  in Saint Petersburg
русских в Санкт-Петербурге
well on Easter there is usually a religious procession
ну в Пасху обычно есть крестный ход
quite a lot of people gather well you
собираются достаточно много народа ну
must admit that it is not such a volume
согласитесь что не такие объёмы
but what does it have to do with what volumes they have uh
ну а при чём здесь какие объёмы у них ээ
if we gather people from all the churches
у нас если по всем церквям собрать людей
who we have just a mosque if I
которые у нас просто мечеть если я
remember correctly in Saint Petersburg there is one
правильно помню в Санкт-Петербурге одна
so they all go there well they have
поэтому туда они все и едут ну у них
such a holiday we are a multinational
такой праздник мы многонациональная
country many religions many
страна много вероисповеданий много
people I wonder just what is the
людей вот интересно просто чм в чём
difficulty yes the difficulty is that for
сложность-то да сложности в том что
some reason Russians are not allowed to gather like that
почему-то русским не дают так собираться
but Muslims are allowed
а мусульманам дают
what does it mean they are not allowed who forbids us to the
что значит не дают кто нам запрещает на
religious procession on Easter I don't know why
Пасху на крестный ход я не знаю почему
yes why so simply who all Well
да почему так просто кто все
why did you you stated the thesis that we are
Ну почему вы вы заявили тот тезис что
forbidden to gather let's
нам запрещают собираться давайте
justify it please I just don't
обоснуйте его пожалуйста я просто не
see that you were gathering
вижу что вы собирались
so what you don't see and that we are
так то что вы не видите и что нам
forbidden are probably different things it
запрещают это наверное разные вещи то
means you are afraid to gather yes
значит вы боитесь собираться да
what does it have to do with us being afraid to gather you are
причём здесь мы боимся собираться вы вы
expressing some strange theses
высказываете какие-то странные тезисы ни
without basing them on anything explain
на чём их не основывая объясните
why wait no need let me
почемусу подождите не надо давайте я
ask a question interrupt me when
задам вопрос перебивайте меня когда
I'm interrupting,
перебиваю я
but it's logical, that's logical here,
а логично вот вот тут логично давай
now look, how is it that
теперь смотри да как так получается что
Muslims have become the main driving force in Russia, where did
в России мусульмане стали основной
you get this idea? Because, for
с чего вы это взяли что потому что
example, on the basis of
например на основа на основании вот
this holiday that was going to gather there, I'm
этого праздника что там собирался
explaining because people gather,
объясняю потому что собираются люди
for example, Muslims, Kadyrov, in short, can
например мусульмане Кадыров может короче
take from a Russian guy, he won't get in trouble for it,
взять от русского парня ему за это
on camera, where did you get this idea? Where did
будет на камеру с чего вы это взяли где
you read this? Look, Ramzan
вы это прочитали посмотрите рамзан
Kadyrov took a Russian guy, Nikita
Кадыров взял русского парня Никиту
Zhuravlya, from Volgograd, brought him to Grozny to the pretrial
Журавля из Волгограда привёз в Грозный в
detention center, brought his
СИЗО привёл туда своего
little Adam Kadyrov,
маленького Адама Кадырова
fifteen years old, there, and he beat up
пятнадцатилетнего и он на камеру избивал
this Russian guy on camera, everyone saw this,
этого русского парня это же все видели
well, I didn't see it, I can't. Google it, Google it
ну я этого не видел я не могу заг
now, Kadyrov
Загуглите загуглите сейчас кадыров
beats up. Google it.
избивает загуглите
Well, let's go. Adam Kadyrov beats up. Well,
ну давайте заг адам Кадыров избивает
is there a context for this
ну так а есть контекст данного
event? Yes, yes, there is.
мероприятия да да есть
I'm listening while I'm searching. Can you
так я слушаю пока я ищу вы можете мне
tell me now? I'll google it now too,
рассказать сейчас я сейчас тоже загуглю
so that you don't say that
чтобы вы не говорили что
no, Kadyrov's son knocked down an activist. I see
нет сын Кадырова сбил активиста вижу
shorts for Kadyrov's son.  laws are not written
шорц сыну Кадырова законы не писаны
ukraine today money ukraine today
украина сегодня гроши украина сегодня
money
гроши
so eh insider Adam Kadyrov the path of the
так э инсайдер Адам Кадыров путь
successor Kadyrov's son and PR for
преемника сын Кадырова и пиар на
the beating but this is all Ukrainian media give
избиение но это всё украинские СМИ дайте
me please some specifically
мне пожалуйста какой-нибудь там именно
Ukrainian there is so look well here I am
украинский есть так посмотрите ну вот я
looking looking for something I am still there is a video well
ищу ищу что-то я пока там видео даже
look even if the video the video is
есть ну смотри даже если видео видео ж
not this story with the story with the son
не у это историю с историю с сыном
Kadyrov I do not comment on the reaction to the
Кадыров не комментирую реакция на
beating Kadyrov even on his Instagram
избиение кадыров даже в своём Инстаграме
it was published wait wait
это было опубликова подождите подожди
Vladimir Putin Dmitry Peskov when you
владимир Путин Дмитрий Песков вот когда
comment on the video in which the son of the head of
комментируеш видео на котором сын главы
Chechnya Adam beats up the accused of burning the
Чечни Адам избивает обвиняемо в сожении
Koran
Корана
Nikita
никита
Zhuravlya I will start talking about Zhuravlya talking
Журавля заговорюсь что Журавля заговорию
with his son damn I will not ranedre said that he is
с сыном блин не буду ранедре заявил что
proud of his son's behavior
гордится поведением
so well and how did this whole
так ну и чем закончилась вся эта
story end should well like if there is an eye
история долж ну как бы если есть оглазка
then there is nothing nothing ended
значит есть ничего ничего закончилось
ended that Adam Kadyrov was given
закончилось то что Адаму Кадырову дали
another orzhen
ещё один оржден
no but this here Zhuravlya yes he
нет а вот этот вот журавель да он
wrote  statement to the police and why did he
написал заявление в полицию и зачем он
burn the Koran uh he was doing some kind of action
сжёг Коран ээ он какую-то акцию делал
there in Volgograd I don't know burned or burned yes
там в Волгограде не знаю сжёг не жёг да
what kind of action he it is written he
он какую какую акцию он он написано он
burned but he burned he burned yes with some if
нажёг но он жёг он жгн да с каких-то
you know If you know and
если вы зна Если вы знаете а
really with some reason he burned the
действительно с каких-то смой он сжёг
Koran yes they took him detained yes
коран да его взяли задержали да
Russian police but for some reason
российская полиция но почему-то вне
illegally people from Chechnya came for him and
закона за ним приехали люди из Чечни и
took him away in Chechnya I turned off the sound for you
забрали его в Чечне я тебе звук отключил
when I tell you people took you will
когда я тебе говорю забрали люди ты
now disappear because you realized that
сейчас сольёшься потому что ты понял что
you People from Chechnya took him to the pre-trial detention center of
ты Люди из Чечни забрали его в СИЗО
Chechnya yes although he should have been in
Чечни да хотя он должен был быть в
Volgograd yes they brought the son of the head of the
Волгограде да привели туда сына главы
republic there to the pre-trial detention center to a stranger and
республики в СИЗО к чужому человеку да и
he was defenseless uh Kadyrov's son beat him
его беззащитного ээ избивал сын Кадырова
in the pre-trial detention center how do you rate this and nothing
в СИЗО как вы оцените это и ничего ему
happened to him for this they gave him a medal
за это не было за это ему дали медаль
now
сейчас
I repeat to you again that if he burned
ещё раз вам повторяю что если он сжёг
Koran yes for the Muslim population
Коран да для мусульманского населения
Koran is a sacred book, I do
Коран - это священная книга вот я
not support this action
нисколько не поддерживаю данное действие
that Ramzan Kadyrov committed at all, but at the
которое совершил Рамзан Кадыров но в то
same time I will tell you that for burning the
же время я вам скажу что за сожение
Koran conditionally I do not remember where in
Корана условно я не помню где в
Holland, in my opinion, the last time there
Голландии по-моему последний раз случай
was a case and a person just like
был да и человека просто
that, wait, you have laws of the
так подождите у вас у вас есть законы
Russian Federation, yes I am asking according to the laws of Russia,
Российской Федерации да я спрашиваю по
according to the laws of the Russian
законам росй по законам Российской
Federation, can I not study it, can I
Федерации может ли я не изучал может ли
watch again and listen to the end of the question, can the law of the Russian Federation,
ещё раз смотри и дослушай вопрос может
yes, uh, the
ли по закону Российской Федерации да ээ
son of the head of the republic come to the pre-trial detention center and
сын главы республики прийти в СИЗО и
beat up a Russian, I
избивать русского
repeat to you again that I have not studied
ещё раз вам повторяю что я не изучал
this issue, I do everything, let's do it this way, we just tell you,
данный вопрос я всё давай так мы тебе
you go,
просто говорим ты идёшь
just subscribe to our Telegram right
просто подпишись на ми Telegram прям
now, that's it, and the
зараз ось він а
priest, this is very and very important, YouTube is
попик це дуже и дуже важливо youtube
driving us through the cards into a shadow ban and
заганяе нас через карки в тіньовий бан и
a lot of videos are not shown to people,
дуже багато відео не показуется людям
information about streams is not shown at times
вчасно не показуется інформація про
Therefore, in order for us to have a
стрими тому для того щоб ми мали
quick connection, subscribe directly
оперативный зв'язок підпишиться прямо
immediately and there is a pop there in the telegram okmdeo, there is
зараз а попик там в телеграмі окмдео ще
also useful and useful information and we are
теж цікава и корисна інформація и мы
obliged to provide you with a permanent
повинні з вами тримати постійний
operational connection, regardless of which we
оперативный зв'язок незалежно від того
will show you about this YouTube glory
чи покаже вам про цей YouTube слава
Ukraine subscribe
Україні підпишись